Shrikant Sharat Kandula

\(+91 98674 88842

https://sharats.me GitHub: sharat87

in LinkedIn: sharat87

♀ Mumbai, India

₩ Born: 8th March 1988.

I love programming, statistics and financial engineering related subjects. To that end, I graduated with Information Systems from BITS Pilani university and have cleared the Level 1 subjects of Actuarial Sciences with IFoA, London.

I intend to work with a reputed software product firm that leverages my experiences and involves challenging problem solving. Preferably in Bangalore, Hyderabad or Dubai. Remote working is also okay and have more than six months experience working remotely.

I hold a 10-year B1/B2 US Visa valid till 27-Dec-2021.

Programming

Languages – I love learning new languages!

Very comfortable with Python, JavaScript (+
HTML & CSS, ES6), Java, SQL, bash, & PHP.
Can also do R, Haskell, Ruby, Clojure, Scala & C.

Editing tools

Very experienced Vim & IntelliJ IDEA user. I maintain a personal license for IntelliJ Ultimate.

Versioning Tools

Experienced git (& GitHub) user. Also worked with Mercurial, Subversion, CVS and Microsoft TFS.

Database Systems

Comfortable with SQLite, Oracle & MySQL.

Actuarial (IFoA)

Following is a list of subjects cleared with the Institute & Faculty of Actuaries.

- 1. CT1 Financial Mathematics
- 2. CT2 Finance & Financial Reporting
- 3. CT3 Probability & Mathematical Statistics
- 4. CT4 Models
- 5. CT5 Contingencies
- 6. CT6 Statistical Models
- 7. CT7 Business Economics
- 8. CT8 Financial Economics

Data Science

Complete "Data Science with R" track from Data Camp. View Certificate.

Professional Experience

S&P Global, Mumbai

November 2017 — Present

Senior Software Developer

- Part of a new and small team developing custom client indices on a platform built on Java and Jython.
- Migrated several tens of indices that were previously calculated manually using Excel models, to writing the calculation methodology in Python (specifically, Jython).
- Involves understanding the calculation methodology behind the index, developing an algorithm for the index and implementing it in a Jython script.
- Strive for high accuracy calculation, accurate to 15-18 significant digits of the index value.
- Serving as the Scrum Master for my team from July 2019.

Calypso Technology, Inc. — Mumbai

December 2014 — November 2017

Technical Consultant

- Worked as a consultant in Calypso's Professional Services organisation and worked on some important implementation projects.
- In Dubai, I was part of a three-member team implementing ERS (Calypso's Risk solution) with the Emirates-NBD bank. We implemented the risk solution according to client's requirements and deployed Credit Risk, VaR / Market Risk and Compliance infrastructure.
- I was part of the team developing interfaces with various external systems such as Quintillion and HDFC as part of the implementation project for Letterone, London. Many of these interfaces have been merged into Calypso core later on.
- I have also initially been part of developing Calypso's one-click-deployment (OCD) solution that standardises and simplifies Calypso's deployment procedures and practices.

Associate Technical Analyst

- Worked as a support analyst for the core infrastructure of the Calypso software system.
- Worked with a team spanning time zones and clients all over the world.
- As a part of this I had a chance to communicate with people from across the world and resolve problems effectively and efficiently.
- Internally, I also automated various processes within the team, helping the entire team work more efficiently.

KNOLSKAPE Solutions Pte. Ltd. — Bangalore

June 2009 — December 2010

Software Developer / Team Lead

- We used web technologies to build simulation games for management students by simulating a limited interactive corporate environment. The simulations were initially based on Flex & ActionScript but we moved on to plain old HTML and JavaScript with jQuery.
- Led a finance training module software for MBA students which has been used in organisations such as INSEAD Business School and JP Morgan.
- Designed and developed a training simulation game that trains the players on change management within an organisational hierarchy.
- Developed a search system for institution wide available resources to be used by students and staff alike, at the time used by INSEAD.
- Worked on a simulation game that trains on Supply Chain Management within an industry as a whole.

INSEAD Business School — Fontainebleau, France July 2008 — December 2008 Semester Internship

- This is a part of the Practice-School (PS-2) Program at my University.
- I worked in the Centre for the Advanced Learning Technologies (CALT) where I got a chance to contribute to an EU funded project, Laboranova.
- As part of that project, we developed a web-based flash application (using Flex) for engaging users and encouraging innovation within the client organization.
- \circ At the time, we had Fiat and AlfaRomeo as our clients for this product.

Practice School Division, BITS — Pilani, Rajasthan January 2008 — May 2008

Professional Assistantship

- This project has been taken up as active participation to improve the systems and software used by my university.
- It involved the recovery and remake of an old project, 'WEPSIMS'(Web Enabled Practice School Instruction Monitoring System, an online portal for instructors at Practice School – II) in Java, using the Java Servlets web development framework.
- The WEPSIMS package is used by the instructors in Practice School 2 programmes to track and report the progress of all the PS-2 programs worldwide.

Hetero Drugs, Hyderabad

May 2007 — July 2007

Summer Internship

- o This internship was part of the Practice School Programme at our University.
- We Analyzed the Organisational Structure and the applications they used for monitoring their security systems.

Education

Institute & Faculty of Actuaries,

London, UK

The Actuarial Fellow qualification Cleared 8 subjects from the CT series so far

Birla Institute of Technology & Science (BITS),

Pilani, India

Aug 05 — May 09 M.Sc [Tech.] Information Systems

Additional Notes

1. Hobbies include reading on my Kindle and playing on my XBox with my wife.

Built from hand crafted HTML, CSS & JS by Shrikant Sharat Kandula.

Last edited on December 11, 2019.

Fonts from Google Fonts.

Icons from Font Awesome by Dave Gandy.